PETYA NIKOLOVA

petia_182@yahoo.com | 07783160859 25 Cuff Point, Columbia Road, E2 7PP

I am a Junior Full-Stack Developer, specialising in Ruby on Rails, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL. As part of my education at LeWagon coding bootcamp I developed profound understanding of how to design, code and ship to production responsive web applications using Ruby on Rails. I learned the foundations of software engineering and database architecture, practised Github collaborations and gained valuable technical skills. I am a hard worker with growing passion towards new technologies and a constant desire to learn and develop professionally.

SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, PostgreSQL, Heroku, GitHub

EDUCATION

LeWagon

October 2016 - December 2016

London, United Kingdom

Le Wagon is a 9 week intense Ruby on Rails focused bootcamp. During the course I have learned HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, git, GitHub, Heroku and Ruby on Rails. Final project during the last 2 weeks was to built a fintech application (www.likeminded.tech).

Projects:

www.like-minded.tech www.petyanikolova.com

Sofia University St. Kliment Ohridski

October 2007 - May 2012

Master of Laws (LLM)

Second-class honours, upper division (2:1)

French Language School "Antoine de Saint Exupery"

September 2000 - June 2005

French language and literature - A-level

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

January 2017 - February 2017

LeWagon

London, United Kingdom

Helping students with their day-to-day coding challenges, explaining fundamental concepts in Ruby language.

B2B Account Manager

January 2016 - October 2016

FlatClub

London, United Kingdom

As part of the business development team at FlatClub I was responsible for carrying out account developing and relationship management activities to maximise sales. I was the main liaison between FlatClub and the corporate clients, ensuring the service is delivered up to standard.

Legal Advisor

August 2015 - December 2015

Notary Office

Sofia, Bulgaria

I was part of a small team at a private notary office and was mainly responsible for writing and preparing legal documentation for estates sales, deeds, powers-of-attorney etc. I was in charge of maintaining and updating the notary archive as well as consulting clients on legal notary matters.

Exam Invigilator and Supervisor

October 2013 – August 2015

British Council

Conducting, invigilating and supervising exams such as IELTS, ACCA, FCE, CAE, CPE, YLE, Aptis, CIMA, CIPD, Edexcel, NEBOSH, etc., as well as various university exams, taken in Bulgaria by distance learners (University of London, University of Sheffield, Brighton college, Brunel university, Loughborough university, Nottingham university, King's college etc.). I was chosen to conduct the GCE exams of the England national under 17 football team in 2015 which were held in Bulgaria due to their participation in UEFA U17 Championship.

Co-founder

April 2010 - December 2012

Regihelp Ltd. Sofia, Bulgaria

As a co-founder of Regihelp I was responsible for expanding the business, reaching out to and bringing in new clients and partnerships. I was mainly focusing on conducting commercial law legal advice, registration of commercial companies as well as making additional changes to the companies, liquidation and deletion of commercial companies, VAT registration, registration of data controllers in CPDP. In addition to that I was keeping the business correspondence by e-mail and by telephone, maintaining corporate records, designing our company's website, logo and brochures, making corporate stamps.

OTHER SKILLS AND PERSONAL INTERESTS

Languages - Fluent in English, Bulgarian (Mother tongue), basic French and Russian.

Sports - Active snowboarder for more than 8 years. Tennis, swimming, table tennis.

Music - Practised drums for more than 8 years, formed my own band in high school, performed over 40 gigs around Bulgaria and recorded one studio album.

Travel - Passionate traveler with an interest in different cultures and cuisines.